Guide to the Latin American political posters, 1972-2001
Department of Special Collections
Latin American political posters,
1972-2001
Mss Prints 0049
29 posters in 1 map folder.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The emphasis of this artificial collection made by a book dealer is Latin American political events occurring in the San Francisco Bay Area. There are also posters originating in Mexico and Central and South America.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2001.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
There are also posters originating in Mexico and Central and South America.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
San Francisco (Calif.)--History--20th century.; Latin America--Politics and government--20th century.; Posters.
Collection Contents
- AMS, El Salvador, "Dia Internacional del Niño," 1988
- Barrios Gallery, Sacramento, "Cannery Workers" by Estaban Villa & Christine Peneyra, Feb.4, no year
- Canto para toda America, Mercedes Sosa en concierto acompanamiento Domingo Cura, nd
- Centro Wifredo Lam, Cuarta Bienal de La Habana 1991
- CGH, UNAM, "Veneno sobre las conciencias: eso es lo que producen la radio y la television. No creas nada de lo que dicen!" [1999?]
- Che, 1928-1967. "No hay fronteras en esta lucha a muerte,"nd
- Comision Nacional de la Mujer, "Dia Internacional de la Mujer," March 8, 1999
- Comite ProPremio Nobel de la Paz 1986 para Rosario Ibarra. Por la Vida y la Libertad para Nuestra America, [1986]
- Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador, Stop Bombing El Salvador, nd
- Consejo General de Huelga (CGH), criticizing UNAM support to presidential candidates and Mexican president Zedillo, [1999]
- Easter Sunday memorial service for El Salvador", Stanford, April 19, 1981
- El Teatro Campesino, La Pastorela, 1983
- El Teatro Campesino, La Pastorela, 1985
- "En el 8 de Marzo Dignas, Valientes, Decididas en la Lucha por la paz" AMNLAE, nd
- Federacion de Clinicas Rurales, El Teatro Campesino en "La Gran Carpa de los Rasquachis," nd
- Festival de los Teatros Chicanos, San Jose State University, Jun.15-24, no year.
- Festival del Sexto Sol, Encuentro de escritores y poetas, Stanford University, nd
- Galería de la Raza event presenting Rivera, Orozco and Siqueiros' works, 1972
- Galería de la Raza event presenting Rivera, Orozco and Siqueiros' works, 1974
- Help Stop U.S. Arms Shipments to El Salvador, protest, Concord, CA, Mar. 24, 1983
- Institute for the Study of Nonviolence, Palo Alto. "Support farmworkers, boycott stores carrying nonUFWA products," nd
- "Jornadas de amistad y solidaridad con los desplazados de Chiapas, nd
- July 19 Coordinating Committee. Rally invitation: "Celebrate the 2nd Year of the Nicaraguan Revolution July 19. San Francisco, nd
- Laney College/Oakland Museum, Cinco de Mayo celebration (CXII aniversario), nd
- Love and Rockets #5, "Now BiMonthly!" nd
- Love and Rockets [logo on black & white with red heart], nd
- "Lucrecia for mayor...The only progressive," nd
- Mobilization for Peace, Jobs and Justice, San Francisco rally, April 30, 1988
- [Palacio de Bellas Artes, Mexico City]; "Vi encuentro internacional de arte popular del cleata Ernesto Che Guevara," 1997 Apr. 1830
- Partido Comunista Revolucionario, "La revolucion es la esperanza...," nd
- Roses in December, prayer service for martyrs of Central America, San Francisco, 1982
- Sindicato Mexicano de Elecricistas, "Que no te engane mas el gobierno; no a la privatizacion de la industria electrica!" nd
- Soldier crucified on a propaganda cross; logos include PRI, PAN, TLC, TV Azteca, Televisa, etc, nd
- U.S. Committee for Justice to Latin American Political Prisoners, Free All Political Prisoners, nd
- U'wa Defense project, John Trudell, San Francisco, 2001
- United FarmWorkers, Malo/ Azteca / Dakila benefit concert, nd
- Western States Mobilization Rally in San Francisco, April 25, 1987